<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[From Dev to Head]]></title><description><![CDATA[I'm a developer starting a new job as Head... Follow my journey!]]></description><link>http://fromdevtohead.net</link><generator>GatsbyJS</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2019 00:03:07 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[New job!]]></title><description><![CDATA[In one month and few days, on the 6th of January, I am starting a new job.
I’m very excited and also a bit scared. My current job title is…]]></description><link>http://fromdevtohead.net/Genesis/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">http://fromdevtohead.net/Genesis/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2019 22:12:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In one month and few days, on the 6th of January, I am starting a new job.
I’m very excited and also a bit scared.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My current job title is Principal Solutions Developer - it is a bit cryptic but basically it means I’m a senior Software Developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now my new title in the new place will be the very prestigious &lt;em&gt;Head of Engineering&lt;/em&gt;!
Yes, I know it sounds very fancy. But the truth is I’ll be the only developer for a while. The company is just starting (yes, it’s a start-up! And yes we have a ping-pong table!) and even if we have plans to start recruitment quickly, it takes time to find good software developers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the past I’ve done a bit of management and I’ve been the Team Lead of nine developers working for a big British bank on a fairly big project.
Still, I realise now that I was not really doing a great job, relying on my memory for task tracking and hoping people would do what I say because I’m a nice guy.
Also, in my current job I am Technical Lead, so I’m supposed to take responsibilities for some parts of the project and I have to influence what people are doing. But nothing like what a &lt;em&gt;Head of Engineering&lt;/em&gt; is supposed to do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the coming months things are going to be very different. In a short period of time I will have to transform the way I work. I’ll have to go from a Developer mindset to a Head of Development one. This is big! A lot to learn and discover. Very exciting!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I would like to try to use this blog to document this transformation, to lay down questions I have and answers I found.
Possibly to start discussions and share with you!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are some many topics! For instance: How do you attract good people? What is a fair and efficient recruitment process? How do you build a good culture in your company? Should we use Python, Javascript? Is Agile dead? …&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll keep you updated on Twitter! But feel free to contact me! &lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>